#### MARCELO AZEVEDO

marcellorhcp@gmail.com Rio de Janeiro - RJ - Brazil https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcelo-azevedohttps://github.com/marcellorhcp

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Working with infrastructure and technical support since 2014, which helped me a lot to develop my soft skills with intense experience solving incidents using ITIL and Agile principles. Impassioned by technology that loves to apply knowledge to solve problems.

Currently studying and practicing software development using Go programming language.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **IT Support and Infrastructure Analyst**

At World Fuel Services
January 2017 - Present

IT Analyst in a global service desk model; managing a backlog of issues and requests, balancing project work alongside day-to-day support.

- I've been working with other IT teams geographically distributed, providing analysis, troubleshooting, maintenance and repair of computer systems and software for effective operation.
- I had the opportunity to be part of the challenge of bringing agile methodology to the company's
  infrastructure and support environment. Worked as an iteration leader conducting the Scrum
  ceremonies like sprint planning, retrospective and daily meetings, helping the other squad members
  to resolve any blockers found in the incidents queue. It was a rotation role to help the team to
  acquire new skills and knowledge as a squad leader.
- I worked on the ERP migration project to Oracle R12 helping external consultants and users to have test, QA, development and production environments working properly.
- Employee of the Year 2019. Won the first place among all employees in WFS Brazil branch.

#### **IT Technical Support**

At Harsco

December 2014 - December 2016

IT Technical support responsible for maintenance and asset control of computers, mobile devices and printers.

 Helped the company to take care of IT infrastructure, Level 1 and Level 2 tickets for Brazil headquarter and remote offices solving incidents using ITIL fundamentals. Improving team metrics and SLAs for critical incidents.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Computer Science**

<u>Unicarioca (Centro Universitário Carioca)</u> June 2013- June 2020

#### **Business Administration**

CEFET-RJ

June 2007- June 2009

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

### **AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner**

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

### **Scrum Foundation Professional**

CertiProof

## **COURSES**

# **Learn How To Code: Go Programming Language**

<u>Udemy - Todd McLeod | Ellen Korbes</u>

Fev - 2022 - Present

## **Web Development using JavaScript**

Cod3r

Fev. 2021- Dec. 2021

# **Discover (Git, GitHub, Linux)**

Rocketseat

Fev - 2021 - Jul. 2021

### SKILLS

### Idioms

Portuguese - native | English - advanced | Spanish - basic